Guide to the BRAC Records 1857-1979
BRAC Records
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
BRAC Records, 1857-1979
5488
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees (BRAC)
967.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, convention proceedings, office files, grievances, legislation, and memorabilia.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees was organized in 1899, and it was the largest single railroad organization for employees who devoted a majority of their time to clerical work of any description including chief clerks, foremen, train announcers, gatemen, checkers; parcel, baggage, and storeroom employees; dock and pier workers; train and engine crew callers; timekeepers; paymasters; freight inspectors; rate and tariff compilers; weigh masters; ticket clerks and sellers; operators of all office and station equipment devices; telephone and switchboard operators; and all employees occupying or performing duties similar to those mentioned. After three months of experience in clerical work employees of both genders, with good moral character, became eligible for membership. The union secured increases in wages and better working conditions for its members.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees
Subjects:
Railroad employees.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
CONTAINER LIST
- 5082: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcript of Hearings Regarding the BRAC, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  0.5 linear feet. Records of the United States National Mediation Board, consisting of the transcript of hearings before Referee Harold M. Gilden, concerning cases deadlocked by committee established by Section 13 of the Agreement of May 1936, Washington, D.C.
- 5086: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcripts Regarding New York Central Railroad Company and BRAC, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  0.5 linear feet. Transcript of proceedings of the National Mediation Board regarding a dispute between the New York Central Railroad Company and certain of its employees represented by the Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees.
- 5488 A: BRAC Chicago Files, 1857-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  103 linear feet. Minutes, board proceedings, constitutions, correspondence, reports, employee agreements, and state laws.
- 5488 A & B mf: BRAC Guides on Microfilm (Box 1, Folder 4)
  1 microfilm reel. Finding aid for collections 5488 A and 5488 B
- 5488 B: BRAC Records, 1915-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  672 linear feet. Grand Lodge Statutes, constitutions, reinstatements, withdrawals, transfers, initiation fee, dues, circulars and publications, bylaws, appeals and grievances.
- 5488 C: BRAC Additional Records, 1921-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  127 linear feet. Proposals, resolutions, convention proceedings, and meeting minutes.
- 5488 D: BRAC Additional Records, 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  10 linear feet. Meeting minutes, correspondence, grievances, treasurer reports, and pamphlets.
- 5488 MB: BRAC Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 8)
  1 linear foot. Constitutions, correspondence, membership cards, and a handkerchief.
- 5735: BRAC Additional Records, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  53 linear feet. Grand Lodge convention materials, information on labor organizations, by-laws, State Federations of Labor by state, information on charitable organizations, educational programs, international affairs and foreign organizations, AFL-CIO reports, Interstate Commerce Commission reports, Railroad Retirement Act, Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act, US Congress and state legislation, activities of Grand Lodge officers, Department of Labor reports, strike information.
- 6187: BRAC, Philadelphia Division, Union Local President Robert Curran Papers, 1956-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  0.5 linear feet. This collection consists of the papers of Robert E. Curran, chairman and president of Local 390, BRAC for the employees of the Reading Company, Philadelphia Division.